Kishor Kumar Sridhar

645 Squaw Creek Drive Unit 203, Ames, IA – 50010 | (515) 708-7091 | kishorkumarsridhar@gmail.com | LinkedIn

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate student in Information Systems with 3+ years of industry experience in data analytics, data science, business intelligence, client/stakeholder engagement, requirement elicitation, project management and database management. Proven experience presenting compelling dashboards and data driven stories to support evidence-based business decision-makings.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Systems, Minor in Statistics (STEM), Iowa State University, GPA – 3.75/4 Dec. 2020 **B.E. in Electrical and Electronics**, Anna University, India, GPA – 7.58/10 May 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: R – tidyverse, ggplot2, leaflet; Python -numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, statsmodels; Git

Databases: MS - SQL Server, MySQL, MS-Access, AWS Redshift

Analytics & Visualization Tools: Power BI, Tableau, R Shiny, MS – Excel, MicroStrategy, Alteryx

Statistical and ML techniques: Regression - Ridge, Lasso regularization; Clustering, Decision Trees, Random Forest, SVM,

Ensemble models, ANOVA, Time Series Forecasting, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow

May 2020 – Aug. 2020

Data Science for Public Good Fellowship, Ames, IA

- Led two Data Science projects to implement an end-to-end Data Science framework using statistical modeling and analyses
- Acquired data through web-scraping, built data pipelines, assessed data governance, and spatially mapped county-level composite indicators of Social and Natural Assets related to upward economic mobility
- Communicated analytical findings to non-technical audience using R Shiny dashboard for assessing community well-being in Iowa
- Spatially map geo-coded data reflecting substance abuse treatment & recovery centers for 99 Iowa counties using R Shiny dashboard
- Turned statistical models into data products to improve public awareness of State resources related to mental and physical health, education & childcare for evidence-based policy-making in statewide substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs

Data Science Intern June 2018 - May 2020

Iowa Department of Transportation (DOT), Ames, IA

- Implemented a regression predictive model with R² of 0.85 to estimate customer wait-times for live display on DOT website
- Performed hypothesis testing, statistical modeling on pavement conditions and created Power BI dashboards to recommend insights
- Applied topic modeling with coherence score of 0.45 on 10,000 public feedbacks to identify factors governing highway maintenance
- Developed efficient SQL scripts for data cleansing, transformation and data modeling for ad-hoc analysis and reporting

Data Analyst Intern

May 2018 – Aug. 2018

Iowa State University, Ames, IA

- Conducted variance analyses within departments in Tableau to identify spending gaps and story lined the results to stakeholders
- Performed factor analysis, What-If analysis on purchase trends of departments facilitating 20% savings in vendor contract renewals

Business Analyst Aug. 2016 – Oct. 2017

Torus, Chennai, India

- Automated insurance claims processing systems with integrated document management to reduce turn-around time by 30%
- Used elicitation techniques such as JAD, brainstorming, document analysis, prototyping to document detailed feature requirements
- Defined the scope of projects by translating requirements into Epics, User Stories and running Sprints with clear timeframes
- Assisted in planning, development, implementation of multivariate & A/B testing to improve conversion rate based on various KPIs

Programmer Analyst

Feb. 2014 – July 2016

Infosys, Chennai, India

- Performed extensive data governance activities using Enablon EHS tool for a data migration project to modernize legacy systems
- Improved database performance by reducing query execution time by 50% using efficient SQL queries and stored procedures
- Communicated as a liaison between the client and technical team to deliver key business solutions using Agile methodologies
- Leveraged Microsoft SSIS to transform data for ETL processes; coordinated with QA teams to execute UAT cycles

LEADERSHIP